MICHAEL KHA

Software engineer adept at abstract and low-level concepts from an architect's approach. Capable of researching and applying unfamiliar technologies by comparing use cases, alternatives, and trade-offs. Proficient with scaling and automated deployment of systems. Pursuing positions relevant to full-stack, cloud, and data infrastructure.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. in Software Engineering | Cooperative Education - GPA: 3.7

Rochester Institute of Technology

Minors: Mathematics, Computer Science

08/2017 - 05/2021

Applied engineering to software development life cycle through computer science principles, projects, and co-ops. Involved in: Society of Software Engineers - Mentor | RIT AI Club - Member | codeRIT - Member

SKILLS

Languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, C/C++
Technologies: Git, React (Hooks/Redux), OpenCV

Design: Algorithm Design & Analysis, Design Patterns,

Distributed Systems, Microservices, Security

Data: SQL, NoSQL, Kafka, Spark, Cassandra, Hadoop

Cloud Providers: AWS, GCP, Azure

DevOps: Vagrant, CloudFormation, Terraform, Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD, Web Server Infrastructure

EXPERIENCE

Al Software Engineer Intern | IOMAXIS - Remote

05/2020 - 08/2020

- Introduced MLOps to automate workflows and shift research business model to development on AI team
- · Researched automated Al workflow platforms (such as Airflow) used by tech companies in production systems
- · Proposed distributed ETL pipeline to centralize data, while automating data extraction and pre-processing
- · Led flexible automated deployment of service using Vagrant, agnostic to AWS or on-premise environment
- · Integrated Kubernetes for configuration, resource management, and scaling of Kafka
- · Kafka, Spark, Cassandra, AWS, Vagrant, Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes, Jira, Scrum

Cloud Software Developer Intern | IOMAXIS - Arlington, VA

01/2020 - 05/2020

- Refined hybrid cloud security concept to a functional product, automating builds using major cloud services
- · Created Flask API endpoints with OAuth2.0 bearer authentication to secure user access to build details
- Optimized quota requests to determine valid regions using multiprocessing, reducing request time by 50%
- · Configured deployment environments and error logging to perform QA build verification and mitigate new errors
- · Python, JavaScript, React, SQLite, AWS, GCP, Azure, Docker, Ansible, Bamboo, Jira, Scrum

Software Engineer Intern | Norfolk Southern - Atlanta, GA

05/2019 - 08/2019

- Implemented changes to database API, recording status of 180,000 monthly cars at terminals and on the line
- Attained insight on domain knowledge and disaster recovery practices for software impacting 30% of revenue
- · Java, Python, C, Perl, Db2 SQL, Jenkins

Teaching Assistant | Rochester Institute of Technology - Rochester, NY

08/2019 - Present

- Supporting cloud course with topics in architecture, containerization, automated deployment, and big data
- · Previously assisted system design course that introduces design patterns, APIs, metric analysis, and refactoring

PROJECTS

Senior Capstone Project | % addletic.com - League Management and Social Platform

- Development of sports league management Diango application with product owner and customer clients
- Overhauling client-side state management and AWS server deployment to deliver functional product
- · Python, TypeScript, React, Jest, Enzyme, Postgres, AWS, Docker

Cloud Microservice Simulation | ○ burger-order-microservice

- Proof of concept to orchestrate microservices on ECS using SQS messaging to manage seguential tasks
- Auto-scaling of services triggered from SQS request traffic using CloudWatch metrics
- · Ruby, React-Rails, AWS, DynamoDB, Docker